<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fletcher&#39;s Cloud Journey</title>
    <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fletcher&#39;s Cloud Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 07:27:16 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloud.fskelly.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Azure Virtual WAN to connect to Azure VMware Solution</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2022/poc-vwan-avs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 07:27:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2022/poc-vwan-avs/</guid>
      <description>How do I connect my on-premises environment to AVS in a quick and simple way? There are a few patterns available for connecting Azure VMware Solution to your on-premises network. There is specific guidance for PRODUCTION deployments here here. The option we are talking about here is for a different use case.
Specific use case: A PoC (Proof of Concept) type environment or smaller environments for testing with a plan to grow after the fact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure VMware Solution: To &#39;Internet Enabled&#39; or not?</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2022/avs-to-internet-able-or-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 16:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2022/avs-to-internet-able-or-not/</guid>
      <description>Guest Post Author: Robin Heringa
What else do I need to know when using Azure VMware Solution (AVS)?
As you all (probably) know by now Azure VMware Solution is a managed service offered by Microsoft providing a managed VMware vSphere environment to customers. With this offering customers no longer need to worry about hardware maintenance, hardware refresh and software maintenance for the core VMware components (ESXi, vCenter and NSX-T).
By default, after initial deployment of Azure VMware Solution, virtual machines do not have the ability to egress to the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I want to use Azure VMware Solution, what should I know about networking?</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2022/new-to-avs-nomon-networking-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 16:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2022/new-to-avs-nomon-networking-1/</guid>
      <description>Author: Fletcher Kelly
What else do I need to know when using Azure VMware Solution (AVS)?
Networking Edition
I have been working with many customers over the last little while that are looking at Azure VMware Solution (AVS).
Often the idea and use case for the customer is correct. There are a few great reasons to use AVS. If you fit within the use cases, you are in for a real treat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Graph - More queries for Networking and Management Groups</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/2021-arg-networking-mgmt-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/2021-arg-networking-mgmt-more/</guid>
      <description>Just some more queries I have developed.
Networking Don&amp;rsquo;t create unnecessarily large virtual networks (for example, /16) to ensure that IP address space isn&amp;rsquo;t wasted.
resources | where type == &amp;#34;microsoft.network/virtualnetworks&amp;#34; | extend addressSpace = todynamic(properties.addressSpace) | extend addressPrefix = todynamic(properties.addressSpace.addressPrefixes) | mvexpand addressSpace | mvexpand addressPrefix | extend addressMask = split(addressPrefix,&amp;#39;/&amp;#39;)[1] | where addressMask &amp;lt;= 16 Smallest recommended size for a GatewaySubnet is /27
When you are planning your gateway subnet size, refer to the documentation for the configuration that you are planning to create.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Group Enterprise Scale Landing Zone queries</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/arg-mg--query-quick-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 05:58:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/arg-mg--query-quick-post/</guid>
      <description>Azure Resource Graph Examples This is just a quick post. I am slowly working on building a collection of Resource Graph Queries - they can be found here and will grow over time. It just takes some time to build these.
They will be broken down into a folder structure based upon the Critical Design Areas of Enterprise Scale Landing Zone
Hope this helps and keep an eye out for more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicep Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/bicep-troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 05:40:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/bicep-troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>Some basic &amp;ldquo;troubleshooting&amp;rdquo; with Azure Bicep So, let me start with this. The team and the community behind Azure Bicep are amazing. There are some great examples here. I often use these as a base and the rip apart or add to meet my needs, you do NOT need to start from ground zero. :smile:
When you are deploying bicep templates you command will look something like this.
$bicepFile = &amp;#34;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cli List Locations and Peers</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/cli-list-locations-and-peers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 07:03:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/cli-list-locations-and-peers/</guid>
      <description>How to use the Azure CLI to list Azure Locations and their peers So this will be a &amp;ldquo;quick post&amp;rdquo; that shows some great functionality within the Azure CLI with az account list-locations. With this command you can expect some output like below, you actually get a lot of content back.
{ &amp;#34;displayName&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Brazil Southeast&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;id&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;/subscriptions/949ef534-07f5-4138-8b79-aae16a71310c/locations/brazilsoutheast&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;metadata&amp;#34;: { &amp;#34;geographyGroup&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;South America&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;latitude&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;-22.90278&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;longitude&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;-43.2075&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;pairedRegion&amp;#34;: [ { &amp;#34;id&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;/subscriptions/949ef534-07f5-4138-8b79-aae16a71310c/locations/brazilsouth&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;brazilsouth&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;subscriptionId&amp;#34;: null } ], &amp;#34;physicalLocation&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Rio&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;regionCategory&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Other&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;regionType&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Physical&amp;#34; }, &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;brazilsoutheast&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;regionalDisplayName&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;(South America) Brazil Southeast&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;subscriptionId&amp;#34;: null } If you look at some of the examples, you will also see some &amp;ldquo;logical&amp;rdquo; locations, example below, there is a way of adding a query to remove these to display only &amp;ldquo;physical&amp;rdquo; locations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Rest Api Postman Basics</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/azure-rest-api-postman-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 09:02:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/azure-rest-api-postman-basics/</guid>
      <description>Absolute basics with Azure and PostMan Getting started Many of the articles I have found online with regards to the Azure REST API assume a fair level of familiarity with Azure which can be a good and bad thing. You see the Azure Portal makes interacting with the Azure REST API very easy as a lot of the &amp;ldquo;prerequisite&amp;rdquo; work is done in the portal as part of the process. For this blog post we will work on something quite basic, &amp;ldquo;Create a Virtual Machine&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expiring Keys and Secrets within Azure Key Vault</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/expiring-keys-azure-key-vault/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 07:06:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/expiring-keys-azure-key-vault/</guid>
      <description>I was working with a customer the other day and a fairly simple ask came up, I however could not find an immediate answer within the portal.
How do I check for expiring keys within the Azure KeyVault?
Now being a PowerShell person, I never gave this much thought as for most tasks or actions I perform on the Azure Platform is done through PowerShell, AP, or CLI. So easy enough, however, not everyone knows how to do this in PowerShell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Ghost Cms and Cdn</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/azure-ghost-cms-and-cdn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 07:00:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/azure-ghost-cms-and-cdn/</guid>
      <description>I moved my blog onto HUGO. Not everyone would want to do this necessarily, there is a bit of a learning curve, part of the reason I DID IT :). However there are other platforms you can use and still add more functionality if you want.
You can use Ghost and add an Azure CDN. This is what this blog post will cover.
There are some very clever people out there that have made this very easy for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My New Blog Home with Azure Static Web App</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/my-new-blog-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 15:57:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/my-new-blog-home/</guid>
      <description>So, I have spent the last few days / weeks deciding the best way to host a blog. Now I have a decidedly &amp;ldquo;split personality&amp;rdquo;. By this I mean I like to segregate my work and personal hobbies. This can be quite beneficial as this allows me to test a few things.
A few key decisions  Must be version controlled - good practice and forces me to get more familiar with git.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Who Am I? I am a Microsoft Employee, working within Azure Engineering as a FastTrack For Azure (FTA) Engineer, focusing primarily on Infra and working with customers across the globe with their respective journeys to the cloud. I was previously a Cloud Solutions Architect (CSA) for Microsoft as well. I was in the Microsoft Partner space for many years before that.
What is FastTrack For Azure? FastTrack for Azure is a technical enablement program for organizations with cloud projects that enables the rapid, effective design, and deployment of Azure solutions in the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Blog</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/page/about/</guid>
      <description>The Blog This is just my personal blog of Azure Code and Azure Experiences. I use mainly PowerShell. I have other repos focused on other scripting languages like az cli, Terrafrom and REST API calls. I am constatly testing, changing or adding contnet, I try to get the code/samples as accurate as possible. Looking to expand content to include more topics and have more people blogging from the FastTrack for Azure team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Fletcher Kelly</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/page/fletcherkelly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/page/fletcherkelly/</guid>
      <description>Who Am I? I am a Microsoft Employee, working within Azure Engineering as a FastTrack For Azure (FTA) Engineer, focusing primarily on Infra and working with customers across the globe with their respective journeys to the cloud. I was previously a Cloud Solutions Architect (CSA) for Microsoft as well. I was in the Microsoft Partner space for many years before that.
What is FastTrack For Azure? FastTrack for Azure is a technical enablement program for organizations with cloud projects that enables the rapid, effective design, and deployment of Azure solutions in the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Robin Heringa</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/page/robinheringa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/page/robinheringa/</guid>
      <description>Robin Heringa Robin Heringa is an engineer in the FastTrack for Azure team at Microsoft working directly with customers on Azure Infrastructure projects. Robin is passionate about all Azure infrastructure technologies with a focus on Azure Management &amp;amp; Security and Azure VMware Solution.
Robin has been with Microsoft for almost 15 years and working on IT Data Center &amp;amp; Cloud projects for 24 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance of Networking Azure</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2019/importance-of-networking-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 16:33:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2019/importance-of-networking-azure/</guid>
      <description>As a start to this blog post, I think it is important to understand how I see my role as a CSA (Cloud Solution Architect) with my customer. I am primarily a trusted advisor and my customers respect what I have to say, I question and challenge my customers in a constructive way to approach the challenge or problem statement in a different way. I have an amazing role of using Azure as my LEGO playpen and then building a custom solution (LEGO model) to help my customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Csa Tools of the Trade</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2019/csa-tools-of-the-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 16:46:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2019/csa-tools-of-the-trade/</guid>
      <description>So a question I often get asked is &amp;ldquo;what tools or products do you use?&amp;rdquo;. So I decided to do a post around the tools and technologies that I personally use on a daily basis. So to start this is what people see on my screen on a daily basis.
This is my most common tool, Visual Studio Code, the version shown above is actually the Insiders Build. The primary reason for this tool is that is a &amp;ldquo;container&amp;rdquo; for other tools and functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/page/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/page/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Security Group Change Alerting</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2019/network-security-group-change-alerting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 08:21:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2019/network-security-group-change-alerting/</guid>
      <description>So, I was with a customer and they are asking for a fairly standard alert.
&amp;ldquo;Please alert me when an NSG is added or modified&amp;rdquo;. Seems simply enough, however this is not as simply as you think. So I used my favourite search and found the following, “How to receive an email on Azure Network Security Group Rule changes“, this is great content and after testing, it works exactly as expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/page/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/page/search/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
