<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog on Fletcher&#39;s Cloud Journey</title>
    <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog on Fletcher&#39;s Cloud Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloud.fskelly.com/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Graph - More queries for Networking and Management Groups</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/2021-arg-networking-mgmt-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/2021-arg-networking-mgmt-more/</guid>
      <description>Just some more queries I have developed.
Networking Don&amp;rsquo;t create unnecessarily large virtual networks (for example, /16) to ensure that IP address space isn&amp;rsquo;t wasted.
resources | where type == &amp;#34;microsoft.network/virtualnetworks&amp;#34; | extend addressSpace = todynamic(properties.addressSpace) | extend addressPrefix = todynamic(properties.addressSpace.addressPrefixes) | mvexpand addressSpace | mvexpand addressPrefix | extend addressMask = split(addressPrefix,&amp;#39;/&amp;#39;)[1] | where addressMask &amp;lt;= 16 Smallest recommended size for a GatewaySubnet is /27
When you are planning your gateway subnet size, refer to the documentation for the configuration that you are planning to create.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Resource Group Enterprise Scale Landing Zone queries</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/arg-mg--query-quick-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 05:58:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/arg-mg--query-quick-post/</guid>
      <description>Azure Resource Graph Examples This is just a quick post. I am slowly working on building a collection of Resource Graph Queries - they can be found here and will grow over time. It just takes some time to build these.
They will be broken down into a folder structure based upon the Critical Design Areas of Enterprise Scale Landing Zone
Hope this helps and keep an eye out for more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Ghost Cms and Cdn</title>
      <link>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/azure-ghost-cms-and-cdn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 07:00:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloud.fskelly.com/post/2021/azure-ghost-cms-and-cdn/</guid>
      <description>I moved my blog onto HUGO. Not everyone would want to do this necessarily, there is a bit of a learning curve, part of the reason I DID IT :). However there are other platforms you can use and still add more functionality if you want.
You can use Ghost and add an Azure CDN. This is what this blog post will cover.
There are some very clever people out there that have made this very easy for you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
